Finding Aid for the Livingston Gearhart Collection of Photographs, 1896-1969
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Additional receipts (2012), circa 1902-1983, II.; Items 26-110
  - Exterior of the maison dite de l'enfer, Chatillon-Coligny, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "L'Enfer - view from the rue de Paradis. Summer of 1939, Chatillon-Coligny" (Box 1, Item lg074)
  - Livingston Gearhart sitting as framed by doorway of the maison dite de l'enfer, Chatillon-Coligny, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Front door - peaked house in background is Paradis. During the wars of religion L'Enfer was a Protestant stronghold; Paradise the Catholic hangout. Chatillon-Coligny, 1939" (Box 1, Item lg075)
  - Livingston Gearhart looking out window possibly in Chatillon-Coligny, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Looking out over the town from my room. Tower on horizon all that remains of a 12th century chateau." (Box 1, Item lg076)
  - Aerial view of Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "As I wrote you a postcard I was right here. Probably Salzburg, 1937" (Box 1, Item lg077)
    City: Salzburg (Austria)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing by a fountain in Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Fountain et moi (1937)" (Box 1, Item lg078)
  - Marketplatz in Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Marketplatz, Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg079)
  - St. George's Chapel steeple in the Festung Hohensalzburg in Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "View from the prince's apartments in the Burg, Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg080)
  - View of trees, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "View of something or other Austrian" (Box 1, Item lg081)
  - View of a valley, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Look hard and you might find an Alp in this one (from the Schloss, Salzburg) (Box 1, Item lg082)
  - View of Festung Hohensalzburg from a distance, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "From another angle. The Burg on Schloss Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg083)
  - View of Festung Hohensalzburg from below, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "The thin spire in the leftern portion of the castle is the little church I took from the window. Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg084)
  - View of the Salzach River in Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Der Fluss dei Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg085)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing at base of a tower, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Believe me, I was not blasé about all this" (Box 1, Item lg086)
  - Livingston Gearhart looking at advertisement on kiosk in Salzburg, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Who do you suppose this guy Toscanini is, with his name plastered all over Salzburg" (Box 1, Item lg087)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Charles Stoppani reclining in chairs in garden, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Charles Stoppani and I in garden path beside the house - Your little Levy has quite Hebraic physiognomy in this one. Wohlen, Suisse, 1938" (Box 1, Item lg088)
    City: Wohlen (Aargau, Switzerland)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing by railing with Lake Lucerne in the background, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Luzern" (Box 1, Item lg089)
    City: Lucerne (Switzerland)
  - View of a mountain valley, 1938?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg090)
  - Livingston Gearhart sitting outdoors, 1938?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "I'll be coming round the mountain" - are these two of the Switzerland repeats? Prob. Lake Lucerne" (Box 1, Item lg091)
  - Bürgenstock Chapel in Switzerland, 1938?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Chapel high up on the Burgenstock (Suisse)" (Box 1, Item lg092)
    City: Bürgenstock (Switzerland)
  - Haystacks, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Haystacks, French style" (Box 1, Item lg093)
  - Remains of the tower of a chateau in Bormes, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "All that remains of 11th century chateau here. We visited dungeons, etc. 8 kilometers of tunnel lead to another town, 11 tons of gold are still hidden in it. Somewhere. Bormes, So. France '39" (Box 1, Item lg094)
    City: Bormes-les-Mimosas (France)
  - Remains of the Bormes chateau, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Remains of the Bormes chateau - didn't come out too well. Mediterranean shore 1939" (Box 1, Item lg095)
  - Person standing at base of the tower of the chateau in Bormes, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Patty against a 14th century tower (Chateau de Bormes) now privately owned by a Parisien who lives in it all summer. He showed us around, gave a most erudite lecture, ex tempore, on architecture, etymological explanation of Borme, etc." (Box 1, Item lg096)
  - View from Bormes towards Mediterranean Sea, 1937 or 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "This was over-exposed. Doubt if you can see that, taken from Bormes, it shows the shore, way down there (mile and a half). Xmas of 1937 or 8." (Box 1, Item lg097)
  - View of the Mediterranean Sea(?) from a distance, 1937 or 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "This is the sight to be seen from window in other picture. The two islands in the distance are where we went fishing." (Box 1, Item lg098)
  - Livingston Gearhart sitting on wall of terrace overlooking Mediterranean Sea, 1937 or 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "On the terrace of our pension. A few feet on the other side lies the Mediterranean of the Cote d'Azur. Note palm tree. Too bad you can't see my sandals, as they are very arty. Xmas time 1937 or 8. (Box 1, Item lg099)
  - Postcard with view of Le Lavandou and its shoreline, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Postcard to Lillian Gearhart. (Box 1, Item lg100)
    City: Le Lavandou (France)
  - Livingston Gearhart playing a flute with Mediterranean Sea in background, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: Livingston, flute, against blurred background of the Riviera. Near Le Lavandou 1938" (Box 1, Item lg101)
  - Postcard with view of the interior of the Gare Saint-Lazare, Salle des Pas-Perdux, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Unaddressed postcard with mention of singer Alice Mary Anderson advertisements. (Box 1, Item lg102)
  - Postcard with view of the Wagenbachbrunnen in Lucerne, 1938?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Unaddressed postcard presumably to Lillian Gearhart (Box 1, Item lg103)
  - Postcard with view of Bookstalls along the Seine, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg104)
  - Postcard with view of Fontainebleau, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Yvon, 1886-1969 Postcard to Lillian Gearhart (Box 1, Item lg105)
  - Sign with slogan from Nazi newspaper, Die Stürmer, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "This sign bears the legend Die Juden sind unser Ungluck - The Jews are our misfortune - I shall always be sorry I went. 1937 Aug." (Box 1, Item lg106)
  - Livingston Gearhart with goatee in profile, 1945, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Orinda Calif." (Box 1, Item lg107)
    City: Orinda (Calif.)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing in front of fence with trees in background, 1949, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Note on verso: "Taken July 1949 … " (Box 1, Item lg108)
  - Portrait of Livingston Gearhart's mother Lillian as a young girl, circa 1902, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Item not in collection; added from another source (Box 1, Item lg109)
  - Livingston Gearhart and his mother Lillian Hawley Gearhart seated at the piano, 1933, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Item not in collection; added from another source (Box 1, Item lg110)
    City: Buffalo (N.Y.)
- Additional receipts (2014), circa 1900-circa 1969, III.; Items 111-192
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Portrait of Livingston Gearhart's grandfather, Colonel George Adelbert Gearhart, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg111)
    City: Unknown location
  - Livingston Gearhart's father, Lynn Gearhart, in topcoat and derby standing in the snow, circa 1916, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg112)
  - Livingston Gearhart as an infant being held by his father Lynn Gearhart on a park bench, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg113)
  - Livingston Gearhart as an infant being held by his father Lynn Gearhart on a park bench, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg114)
  - Livingston Gearhart as an infant being held by his father Lynn Gearhart on a park bench, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg115)
  - Livingston Gearhart as an infant being held by his father Lynn Gearhart outside in a park, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg116)
  - Livingston Gearhart as an infant being held by his father Lynn Gearhart outside a house, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg117)
  - Livingston Gearhart as a toddler sitting inside a baby carriage, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg118)
  - Livingston Gearhart as a toddler sitting inside a baby carriage, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg119)
  - Livingston Gearhart as a toddler sitting inside a baby carriage outside in winter, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: 1917, Granger Place (Box 1, Item lg120)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler on a sled in winter with grandfather George Adelbert Gearhart, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg121)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler on a sled in winter with grandfather George Adelbert Gearhart with the William R. Heath house built by Frank Lloyd Wright in the background, 1917, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: LG with grandpa Geo. Adalbert Gearhart - check if the background is the Frank Lloyd Wright house, Soldier's Place (Box 1, Item lg122)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler held by his mother Lillian Hawley Gearhart, 1920?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: Granger Pl. Buffalo - Madonna and child. (Box 1, Item lg123)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler sitting inside a stroller, 1920?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: L.G. prob. Granger Place. (Box 1, Item lg124)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler drinking water and standing next to a water pump, 1920?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: East Aurora ca. summer 1920. (Box 1, Item lg125)
    City: East Aurora (N.Y.)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler holding a ball, 1920?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: East Aurora ca. 1920 (The "Roycroft") (Box 1, Item lg126)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler sitting in front of fountain, 1920?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: Delaware Park, or Gates Circle, or something like that in Bflo. (Box 1, Item lg127)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler sitting on driveway with his father Lynn Gearhart, 1921?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: Lynn and son cracking nuts, Granger Place (Box 1, Item lg128)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler on driveway with his father Lynn Gearhart, 1921?, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg129)
  - Livingston Gearhart's father, Lynn Gearhart standing on a staircase outside, circa 1920, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: Lynn Gearhart pre-1920 (Box 1, Item lg130)
  - Livingston Gearhart with unidentified woman standing in front of a house, circa 1922, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: LG with (I think) a person we called "Nana". (Box 1, Item lg131)
  - Livingston Gearhart's father, Lynn Gearhart sitting on stairs outside a house, circa 1922, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: probably Lynn (Box 1, Item lg132)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart as toddler seated on a bench, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Beamer, Frank H. (Box 1, Item lg133)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart as toddler standing, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Beamer, Frank H. (Box 1, Item lg134)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart as toddler standing, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Beamer, Frank H. (Box 1, Item lg135)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart as toddler seated on a bench while holding a toy dog, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Beamer, Frank H. (Box 1, Item lg136)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart as toddler seated on a chair, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Beamer, Frank H. (Box 1, Item lg137)
  - Livingston Gearhart as toddler seated outside with his father Lynn Gearhart, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg138)
  - Livingston Gearhart's father, Lynn Gearhart, standing behind a row boat, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg139)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing outside with a toy horse, circa 1921, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: I'd guess Old Lyme, Connecticut (Box 1, Item lg140)
  - Livingston Gearhart as child sitting outside with unidentified person, circa 1923, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg141)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart's father, Lynn Gearhart, circa 1923, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: McGeorge, Robert R. On verso: Lynn Gearhart ca. 1918 (Box 1, Item lg142)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart in naval outfit, circa 1923, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: McGeorge, Robert R. (Box 1, Item lg143)
  - Livingston Gearhart (bottom row, far right) with members of the choir and staff of the Choir School at the Cathedral of St. John the Divine in New York city, circa 1927, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Pach Photograph Co. Third row from the bottom: 3rd from left: Preceptress of the Lower School, Evelyn Selwyn Thornton; 4th from left: Deaconess and Housemother Eliza B. Mills; 5th from left: Rev. W. D. F. Hughes, Headmaster of the Cathedral Choir School effective September 1 1927, 6th from left: Dean of the Cathedral, the Very Rev. Howard Chandler Robbins; 7th from left: Miles Farrow, Cathedral Organist and Master of Choristers; 8th from left: Resident Nurse Mrs. Marian G. White (Box 1, Item lg144)
    City: New York (N.Y.)
  - Livingston Gearhart as young boy with a woman identified as Marion, circa 1929, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg145)
  - Livingston Gearhart with his mother Lillian Hawley Gearhart seated at the piano, circa 1932, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Fox, Charles James, photographer (Box 1, Item lg146)
  - Livingston Gearhart with his mother Lillian Hawley Gearhart and his sister Martha seated at the piano, circa 1932, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Fox, Charles James, photographer On verso: Lillian, Martha, Livingston, 1932? (Box 1, Item lg147)
  - Gathering of people on the lawn outside a house, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: where and when Sasha performed Bach unaccompanied sonatas in my youth (Box 1, Item lg148)
  - Livingston Gearhart (bottom left) with Nadia Boulanger and members of her class of 1938 at the Conservatoire américain de Fontainebleau, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Others include: Nadia Boulanger seated at the piano; Virginia Morley (standing to right of piano in front of man with handkerchief in pocket); Louise Talma, seated 2nd row, left; Ethel Thurston, standing, 2nd from right; Herve Armington, seated on floor bottom right (Box 1, Item lg149)
  - View of Lucerne with Lake Lucerne and the Swiss Alps in the background, circa 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Verlag Globetrotter On verso: Enclosing this little memento of Luzern … (Box 1, Item lg150)
  - Livingston Gearhart, Virginia Morley (Clotfelter), with an unidentified male and female pretending to guzzle from bottles, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg151)
  - Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) standing in front of Mozarts Geburtshaus, 1937, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg152)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) seated at pianos, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg153)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) seated at pianos, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg154)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) sitting outside on stairs of a building in Le Lavandou, 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg155)
  - Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) standing by a gate to a building, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg156)
  - Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) practicing at the piano in the salon at L'Enfer, 1939, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg157)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley (Clotfelter) standing in front of a building, circa 1938, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Inscription in margin: A thrilling conclusion to our week. (Box 1, Item lg158)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley sitting outside on a bench with an unidentified female, undated, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg159)
  - Studio portrait of Livingston Gearhart, circa 1940, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Durfey-Chalon, Frank (Box 1, Item lg160)
  - Four hands of Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley, circa 1940, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Durfey-Chalon, Frank (Box 1, Item lg161)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley outside with a pool in the background, circa 1942, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Percival, Willa, 1916-2009 (Box 1, Item lg162)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley outside with a pool in the background, circa 1942, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Percival, Willa, 1916-2009 (Box 1, Item lg163)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing on a ladder on a porch checking a light fixture, circa 1942, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Percival, Willa, 1916-2009 (Box 1, Item lg164)
  - Livingston Gearhart sitting with tree in background, circa 1942, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified On verso: L. Gearhart, Orcas - West Beach, ca. 1941-2. (Box 1, Item lg165)
    City: Orcas Island (Wash.)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley standing outside, circa 1943, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg166)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley standing outside with a house in the background, circa 1943, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg167)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley standing outside, circa 1943, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg168)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley standing outside with Ernie and Marjorie Farmer of Shawnee Music, and four other people, circa 1943, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified The man on left with glasses may be named F. Dunkl. (Box 1, Item lg169)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley standing outside a building, circa 1943, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg170)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley with the truck used to carry their pianos on tours, with driver Raymond Lee, circa 1943, 1 color photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg171)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley studying a score on a piano, circa 1944, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Abresch, J. (James) (Box 1, Item lg172)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley performing at one piano, circa 1944, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Abresch, J. (James) (Box 1, Item lg173)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley in concert dress, circa 1944, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Abresch, J. (James) (Box 1, Item lg174)
  - Livingston Gearhart working on an arrangement while at the piano, 1945, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg175)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley on a bicycle, 1946, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg176)
    City: Shawnee on Delaware (Pa.)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley playing badminton, circa 1946, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg177)
  - Pencil drawing of Livingston Gearhart dressed as "Sir Lord Livingston", 1948, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Logan, Tom, artist Stamp on verso: Peter A. Juley and Son, photographers of Fine Arts since 1896. (Box 1, Item lg178)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley at an upright piano with a man who is possibly Ed McGinley, author of the volume on the piano, circa 1949, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg179)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley seated at pianos on the set of the Fred Waring television show, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg180)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley performing at pianos on the set of the Fred Waring television show, 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified Accompanied by large-format negative. (Box 1, Item lg181)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley seated at pianos probably on the set of the Fred Waring television show, circa 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg182)
  - Livingston Gearhart and Virginia Morley performing at two pianos in accompaniment to a female singer, probably on the set of the Fred Waring television show, circa 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg183)
  - Livingston Gearhart standing outside with Fred Waring, circa 1952, 1 black and white photograph; Photographer: Unidentified (Box 1, Item lg184)